DEBORAH AMUZU

debamuzudeb@gmail.com| +233 571 270 912 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio | Accra, Ghana

Summary

Frontend Junior Web Developer with a unique background in Agrometeorology, bringing together skills in climate data analysis, seasonal forecasting, and web development. Experienced in developing intuitive, responsive web applications and knowledgeable in climate projection and agrometeorological modeling. Known for a strong analytical mindset and effective communication skills, with a dedication to delivering data-driven solutions through web-based platforms. Enthusiastic about using technology to tackle environmental and agricultural challenges and committed to continuous learning in the field of web development.

Skills

Languages: HTML | CSS | JavaScript |

Frameworks: React | Tailwind | Version Control Systems: Git |

Hosting Platform: Github | Netlify |

Others: CDO

Experience

Corextreme Technologies – Yaoundé, Cameroon| Junior Frontend Developer (Immersion) | 28/10/2024 – Present

Public Market Management Platform to modernize and streamline the management, control, and oversight of public procurement processes in Cameroon.

Specific Tasks:

- UI Framework Setup: Set up the frontend framework (React etc.), ensuring a responsive layout structure for desktop and mobile.
- Create frontend components to display real-time notifications and alerts for end-users.

Ghana Meteorological Agency – Accra, Ghana | Agrometeorologist (Volunteer) | 03/2024 - Present

- Assisted in the 2024 major and minor seasonal forecast
- Trained 11 co-workers on how to make NDVI monitoring maps using ArcMap
- Collect and Analyze climate data.
- Maintain accurate records of meteorological data.

DEBORAH AMUZU

- Assist in Climate and Agrometeorological Seasonal forecasting activities.
- Participate in meetings, and capacity building programs.
- Conduct Research and Report writing.

Ablekuma West Municipal Assembly | Environmental Health Officer | 12/2018 - 2020

- Conducted Routine school and domicile hygiene Inspection
- Conducted hematology test on over 500 food vendors.
- Participated in Data collection for ESICApp (Expanded Sanitary Inspection and Compliance App)
- Carried out administrative roles like filing of complaints

Projects

Personal portfolio | Wedding Website | News App | Advertisement App | Library Management App | Market Management Platform |

Education

- Engineering (Masters 1), Agrometeorology, Graduation: 03/2024
 - **AGRHYMET Regional Center**
 - Second Class Upper (Mention Assez-bien)
- Higher National Diploma, Science Laboratory Technology, Graduation 10/2016
 - Accra Technical University
 - Second Class Upper

Awards & Certifications

- 2024 | Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Innovation: Web Development job Simulation | Forage
- 2024 | Badge in Web Development Fundamentals | IBM SkillsBuild
- 2024 | Best Non-Francophone student out of 6 students | AGRHYMET Regional Center
- 2022 | Attestation in Teledetection | AGRHYMET Regional Center
- 2021 | Attestation in French Language | AGRHYMET Regional Center